Guide to the New-York Historical Society Press Clippings 1843-2014 NYHS-RG 7
New-York Historical Society
- Series II. Subject Files, 1968-2013; 7.67 Linear feet
  - The World of Tiffany: The Egon Neustadt Collection of Tiffany Lamps (2 folders), 1983-1984 (Box 31, Folder 1-2)
    Includes a list of lamps as they appeared in the exhibition.
  - Collecting and Connoisseurship Symposium, 1983-1984 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    This day-long symposium was held on January 21, 1984, and was co-sponsored by the N-YHS and The Magazine Antiques. It presented several panels on the analysis of the art of collecting American silver, painting, porcelain, and furniture.
  - The Sons of St. Patrick: The Irish and Irish Organizations in New York City Before 1900, 1984 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - New York and the China Trade (2 folders), 1984 (Box 31, Folder 5-6)
  - The Adirondacks: A Wilderness Preserved, 1984 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Five New York Families, 1984 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    This exhibition looked at colonial New York through the acquisitions of the following families: the Beekmans, De Peysters, Livingstons, Schuylers, and Van Rensselaers.
  - Waldron Phoenix Belknap, Jr. Collection, 1984 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    This folder consists of materials about the exhibition of the Belknap Collection of oil and watercolor protraits dating from the Colonial, Revolutionary, and Federal periods.
  - Watercolors from the N-YHS Permanent Collection, 1984 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    Includes one paragraph descriptions and brief artist biography of the many watercolors that were on display in the exhibition.
  - Visions of Liberty (2 folders), 1984-1985 (Box 31, Folder 11-12)
  - Lost in the Shuffle: Playing Cards and Board Games from Bygone Days, 1984 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Early Temperance Movements, 1984 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - The City Comes of Age, 1984 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    This folder contains materials about the exhibition celebrating the 180th birthday of N-YHS.
  - A Pageant of Heraldry in Britain and America, 1984 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    Includes a budget for the exhibition as well as An Outline of Heraldry in England and Scotland, a booklet by Robert Innes-Smith.
  - Her Voice Was Heard: Women and Politics in America, 1984 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Struggle for a Continent: France and England in North America, 1983 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - The Baroness Hyde de Neuville: Sketches of America, 1807-1822, 1984-1985 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - General Clippings, 1985 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Centuries of Childhood in New York: A Celebration on the Occasion of the 275th Anniversary of Trinity School, 1984-1985 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Lurid Literature: Popular Reading of the 19th Century, 1985 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Karol Kozlowski, 1885-1969, 1985 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    This exhibition displayed paintings by Polish-American folk artist Kozlowski.
  - Audubon's Birds of North America: The Original Watercolors (3 folders), 1985 (Box 32, Folder 11-13)
  - Metropolis in Mourning: Ulysses S. Grant, 1822-1885, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Gouverneur Morris Chair, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    This folder contains articles about the discovery of this chair, given to N-YHS in 1817. The chair was once owned by statesman Gouverneur Morris (1752-1816) and originally belonged to Marie Antoinette.
  - Statue of Liberty: America's Symbol of Freedom in Souvenirs and Ephemera, 1985-1986 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Chicago and New York: More Than A Century of Architectural Interaction, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Artist in Residence: The North Country Art of Frederic Remington, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - The Great Fire of 1835: Sesquicentennial Anniversary, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - General Clippings (2 folders), 1986 (Box 33, Folder 7-8)
  - Niagara: Two Centuries of Changing Attitudes, 1697-1901, 1986 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Prized Prints: Rare American Prints Before 1860 in the Collection of the N-YHS, 1986 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - James Henry Cafferty, 1819-1869, 1986 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - P.T.Barnum: Prince of Humbug, Merchant of Delight (1 of 2), 1986 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - P.T.Barnum: Prince of Humbug, Merchant of Delight (2 of 2), 1986 (Box 33, Folder 13)
    This folder holds a small scrapbook related to the exhibition.
  - Liberty's Legacy: Photographs of New York's Ethnic Festivals, 1986 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Treasures of Botanical Illustration, 1986 (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Portraits of Power: Paintings from the Collection of the New York Chamber of Commerce and Industry, 1986-1987 (Box 33, Folder 16)
    Folder includes the annual report of the New York City Partnership, Inc. and its affiliates.
  - Storied Shores: Lake George in Legend and History, 1986 (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - A Portrait of Livingston Manor, 1686-1850, 1986 (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - The Pleasure of Your Company: Parties and Balls in New York City, 1986-1987 (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - "Pungent Salt" Article re: Mathew Brady, 1986 (Box 33, Folder 20)
    Includes a reprint from History of Photography, Vol. 10, No. 1 (January-March 1986) of Helena Zinkham's article "Pungent Salt: Mathew Brady's 1866 Negotiations with the New-York Historical Society."
  - Made for New York: Antique Toys from the Lawrence Scripps Wilkinson Collection, 1986-1987 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - General Clippings (2 folders), 1987 (Box 34, Folder 2-3)
  - The Wagstaff Collection of American Silver, 1987-1988 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Government by Choice: Inventing the United States Constitution (2 folders), 1987 (Box 34, Folder 5-7)
  - Jackie Robinson: An American Journey, 1987 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - The Hudson River and the Highlands: The Photographs of Robert Glenn Ketchum, 1987 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - New York Bestiary: Pets and Pests of the Metropolis, 1987 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Strong on Music: The New York Music Scene, 1836-1850, 1987 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    This exhibition's centerpiece was a diary kept by George Templeton Strong, and included paintings, sheet music and prints from 1836-1850.
  - N-YHS Summer Film Festival, 1987 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Jasper F. Cropsey: Artist and Architect, 1987 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Ex Libris Rufus King, 1987 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Encyclopedia of New York, 1987-1988 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - General Clippings, 1988 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - N-YHS Financial Difficulties, 1988 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Blizzard of '88, 1987-1988 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Charmed Places: Hudson River Artists and their Houses, Studios, and Vistas, 1988 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Francis William Edmonds: American Master in the Dutch Tradition, 1987-1988 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Artistic Houses: Lavish Interiors of 19th-Century New York, 1988 (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Rise and Fall of New York: Building and Unbuilding Manhattan, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Arnold Newman: Five Decades, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Putting New York on the Map, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - The Belknap Collection of Silver and Portraits, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Bellows, Bobbins, and Butter Churns: Keeping House in 19th-Century America, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Thanksgiving Harvest: Food and Wine Festival, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Celebrating the Holidays in Old New York, 1988-1989 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    Includes a check list for this holiday exhibition.
  - Flag Paintings of Childe Hassam, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - The Invisible Surface: Paper and the Printing Arts in Early America, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Hard Cider and Hot Air, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - N-YHS History Makers Gala, 1988-1990 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - General Clippings (2 folders), 1989 (Box 36, Folder 12-13)
  - Board of Trustees, 1989-1990 (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Society Reorganization, 1989 (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - Revisiting the 1939 World's Fair, 1989 (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - George Washington in New York, 1989 (Box 36, Folder 17)
  - Jewish Museum Arrangement, 1989 (Box 36, Folder 18)
    Includes photographs of Jewish Museum (Warburg Mansion and List Building) and proposed expansion.
  - Burr McIntosh: Polite Society, 1900-1910, 1989 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Irving Browning: City of Contrasts, 1989 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Cased Images: 150th Anniversary of Photography, 1989-1990 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - An American Sampler: Folk Art from The Shelburne Museum, 1989 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - General Clippings, 1990 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Why History?, 1990 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    This series was presented over a 4-month period, and focused on the ways in which perceptions of history shape daily lives. The series consisted of concerts and films, as well as panel discussions with scholars.
  - Board of Trustees, 1990 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - The Lamps of Tiffany, 1988-1991 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Attorney General's Announcement, 1990 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Nicolino Calyo: 19th Century Views of New York, 1990 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Below the Line: Living Poor in America, 1990 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Lord Cornbury, Royal Governor of Colonial New York, 1990 (Box 37, Folder 12)
    Clippings related to competing claims over whether or not a portrait owned by N-YHS was of Lord Cornbury, Royal Governor of New York from 1702-1708.
  - Mexican Music Concert Series, 1990-1991 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Paris 1889: American Artists at the Universal Exposition, 1990 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - The Thomas Jefferson Bryan Gallery: Changing Attributions, 1990 (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Charles Gilbert Hine: Impressions of a City, 1990 (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - Baseball Story, 1990 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    Relates to a newspaper account of possibly the earliest baseball game played in 1845, discovered in material at N-YHS by a Harvard graduate student.
  - ART What Though EAT: Images of Food in American Art (2 folders), 1990-1991 (Box 38, Folder 2-3)
  - Luman Reed Gallery, 1990-1991 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - General Clippings (2 folders), 1991 (Box 38, Folder 5-6)
  - Jewish Museum Exhibitions at the N-YHS, 1991 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Museum Store, 1991 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Why History? Series: Race and Class in New York City, 1991 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    Includes press attendance list.
  - The Taste of Andrew Carnegie, 1991 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    Includes a print of a photograph of Carnegie from the N-YHS collection (from negative 49533).
  - New York Chapter of the American Institute of Architects Design Awards, 1991 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Justice Rendered: The Courts of New York Colony and State, 1691-1991 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - McKim, Mead, & White's New York, 1991 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - New York in Watercolor: The Landscapes of William Rickarby Miller, 1991 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - While They Fight: The Home Front in New York City, 1991 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Imagining the New World: Columbian Iconography, 1991 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - A Day Without Art, 1991 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - General Clippings, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Forever Wild: The Adirondack Experience, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Ansel Adams: The Early Years, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - The Century Association: American Masters and Masterworks, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Building City Hall: Competition, Construction, and Context, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - N-YHS Financial Difficulties, 1993 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - N-YHS Financial Difficulties / Fiscal Crisis, 1990s (Offsite-box 50)
  - Thomas Cole: Landscape into History, 1993-1994 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Press Coverage Report, 1993 March-1994 March (Box 39, Folder 10)
    Includes photocopies of articles compiled from various news outlets by Resnicow Schroeder Associates, Inc. The articles focus on particular themes, including the publication of the Audubon watercolors and a related traveling exhibition, various other exhibitions, N-YHS's connection to the movie The Age of Innocence, and institutional matters, such as N-YHS's financial difficulties.
  - General Clippings (2 folders), 1994-1995 (Box 40, Folder 1-2)
  - Treasury of the Past, 1995 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Life on a Fiscal Precipice, 1995 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    Includes a photocopy of former Museum Director Holly Hotchner's article about N-YHS in the American Association of Museums publication Institutional Trauma: Major Change in Museums and Its Effect on Staff, edited by Elaine Heumann Gurian.
  - General Clippings, 1996 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - General Clippings, 1997-1998 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - General Clippings, 1999 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - General Clippings, 2000 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - General Clippings, 2001 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - General Clippings, 2002 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - General Clippings, 2003 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - General Clippings, 2004 (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - The Magazine Antiques Issue re: N-YHS, 2005 January (Box 40, Folder 13)
    Issue of Antiques covering aspects of N-YHS collections on the occasion of the 200th anniversary.
  - General Clippings, 2005-2006 (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Slavery Exhibition Coverage, 2005 (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - General Clippings, 2011-2013 (Box 40, Folder 16)
- Series III. Media Coverage Binders, 2004-2009, 2013-2014; 9 Linear feet
  Scope and Contents
  The series includes press clippings, tearsheets, print-outs of articles, summaries of press coverage, and related documents. In large part these were provided to N-YHS by Burrelle's and other media monitoring services. The coverage relates to particular exhibitions as well as to other N-YHS events, programs, etc. A distinguishing feature of this series is that most of the documents were packaged in plastic pouches and stored in binders. In most instances, the materials were removed from the binders during processing.
  Arrangement
  The series retains its original order, which is chronological.
  - Media coverage binders, 2004-2005 (Offsite-box 41)
  - Media coverage binders, 2005 (Offsite-box 42)
  - Media coverage binders, 2005-2006 (Offsite-box 43)
    Includes among the packets one that summarizes media placement during October 2005-April 2006 for the Slavery in New York exhibition.
  - Media coverage binders, 2006 (Offsite-box 44)
  - Media coverage binders, 2006 (Offsite-box 45)
  - Media coverage binders, 2007 (Offsite-box 46)
  - Media coverage binders, 2007 (Offsite-box 47)
  - Media coverage binders, 2008 (Offsite-box 48)
  - Media coverage binders, 2008-2009, 2013-2014 (Offsite-box 49)